Guide to the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Audiovisual Materials, 1956-2018 RL.10006_AV RL.10006_AV
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Audiovisual Materials
1956-2018 and undated, bulk 1950-2018
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.10006_AV
100 Linear Feet 1,337 analogue and digital audiovisual resources
Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel is an advocate for the arts, interviewer, documentarian, teacher, political organizer, and resident of New York City. The Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Audiovisual Collection is primarily comprised of audio and video recordings of programs and interviews produced by Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel for television and print, centering on the arts, architecture, and historic preservation, particularly in New York, from the mid-1970s to the present.
Access Restrictions
Many of the resources in this collection have been digitized for use, and are available via the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Video Archive on YouTube or, by request, on the Duke Digital Repository. Original audiovisual and electronic media are closed to use without written permission from the Donor -- for further information contact Research Services. All researchers requesting copies of audiovisual materials from the collection for purposes other than private study and research are required to present written permission from the donor approving the request. While all master recordings are represented in this guide, the collection contains both copies of master recordings and elements that went in to creating the master recordings. For an inventory of the copies and elements, contact Research Services.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Provenance
The Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift from 1988 to 2018.
Collection Overview
Spanning 1956 to 2018, with the bulk of the materials dating from 1976 to 2018, the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Audiovisual Collection documents the programs produced by a pioneering advocate for art, architecture, historical preservation, and public policy. The collection is comprised of over 1,300 items, including analogue and digital audio and video resources, stemming from Diamonstein-Spielvogel's prolific output of books, educational programming, and interviews, as well as her work in historic preservation. Two hundred programs, including television interviews with notable artists, designers, and architects, and presentations by the Historic Landmarks Preservation Center, have been digitized by Duke University Libraries and are available on the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Video Archive on YouTube. Topics covered by the materials in this collection include broad categories such as art and architecture in the 20th century; historic preservation and the protection of cultural property; media and society; social conditions; and women's rights. Where resources are available on YouTube, links have been provided to the specific video. Audio resources are available through the Duke Digital Repository on request. While all master recordings are represented in this guide, the collection contains both copies of master recordings and elements that went in to creating the master recordings. For an inventory of copies and elements, contact Research Services.
Biographical Note
Throughout her career, Dr. Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel has served as a leading voice on some of the defining urban issues of our time, especially preservation of the historic built environment. She is a pioneering advocate of the arts, with interests in architecture, design and public policy. The first Director of Cultural Affairs for New York City, she brought the first public art to Bryant Park in 1967, and the first public performance by the Metropolitan Opera to Central Park. She was the longest-serving Landmarks Preservation Commissioner in the city's history, spanning the administrations of Mayors Lindsay, Beame, Koch, Dinkins and Giuliani from 1972 to 1987. She has also served as the Commissioner of the New York City Arts/Public Design Commission and of the New York City Cultural Commission, as the Chair of the New York City Landmarks Preservation Foundation (1987-1995), and since 1995 has been the Chair of the Historic Landmarks Preservation Center.
Diamonstein-Spielvogel has served under four presidential administrations. As part of the Johnson staff, she helped create the White House Fellows and Presidential House Scholars Programs, and the White House Festival of the Arts. She was appointed by President Reagan to the board of the U.S. Holocaust Memorial Museum in Washington, D.C.; and by President Clinton to the U.S. Commission of Fine Arts, where she was elected the first woman vice chair in its more than 100-year history. In 2010, President Obama appointed her a commissioner of the American Battle Monuments Commission. She was named the vice chair of the New York State Council on the Arts in 2008 and chair in 2016. In 2012, she was appointed to advise the Port Authority on the integration of public art and architecture into the World Trade Center site. Diamonstein-Spielvogel also has been active in many state and national Democratic campaigns.
Diamonstein-Spielvogel received her doctorate with honors from New York University, and honorary doctorates from the Maryland Institute College of Art, Baltimore, MD; Longwood University, Longwood, VA; and the Pratt Institute, Brooklyn NY. She is the author of twenty books and numerous magazine and newspaper articles and has served as curator of seven international museum exhibitions; in 2013 an exhibit based on her latest book, Landmarks of New York, Vol. V, traveled to 14 cities throughout New York State.
She has served as interviewer/producer of nine television series for the Arts & Entertainment Network in addition to numerous programs for other national networks; many of her interviews with artists, architects, designers, and other notables have been digitized and made available on YouTube as part of the Duke University Video Archive. In October 2010, Duke initiated the Diamonstein-Spielvogel Visiting Filmmaker Series to address contemporary issues of social, political, economic, and cultural urgency from a global perspective.
Diamonstein-Spielvogel has served on the boards of numerous national and local institutions and organizations, including recent service in support of the Fresh Air Fund, the Drawing Committee of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, the Acquisitions Committee of the Cooper-Hewitt National Design Museum, and the N.Y. Museum of Modern Art. She is a founding director of the Highline in New York City and the Trust for the National Mall in Washington, D.C. She has served on many boards including the American Council on the Arts, the White House Endowment Fund, the Municipal Art Society, the Landmarks Conservancy and B.A.M.
Diamonstein-Spielvogel has received numerous awards and honors, including an award from H.E.L.P. in 2001 and lifetime achievement awards from Partners for Livable Places in Washington, D.C. and the Citizens Committee of New York. She also received the Legend designation by the Pratt Institute, Landmarks Lion by the Historic Districts Council in 2010, and tje Elly Award honoring outstanding women leaders in 2012. In fall 2012 she was the recipient of the John Jay Heritage Award.
She is married to international business executive and former U.S. Ambassador to the Slovak Republic, Carl Spielvogel, whose papers are housed in the Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising and Marketing History at Duke University, and she resides in New York City.
Collection Arrangement
Series are arranged alphabetically by title. Within series, subseries are predominantly arranged alphabetically, with some subseries and files arranged chronologically.
Related Material
Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Video Archive on YouTube
For the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Papers, see Guide to the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Collection, 1876-2018 and undated, bulk 1950-2018
Oral histories Dr. Diamonstein-Spielvogel conducted with the Columbia Center for Oral History Program's series Inside New York's Art World are also available through the Columbia University Libraries' Oral History Portal. The portal also provides access to interviews with Kitty Carlisle Hart, Mary Bass Gibson, and Phyllis Cerf Wagner.
DVDs; Microcassettes; Audiocassettes; Oral histories (document genre); Fashion and art.; Audiotapes; Celebrities -- United States -- Interviews; Decorative arts -- United States.; Cultural artifacts.; United States -- Cultural policy; New York (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs; Women and the arts.; Television and art.; Historic preservation -- United States; Videotapes; Film; New York (N.Y.) -- History; Interior decoration -- United States.; Artists -- United States -- Interviews; Arts and society -- United States; Architecture -- United States.; Diamonstein-Spielvogel, Barbaralee; New York (N.Y.). Landmarks Preservation Commission.
- Interviews, 1974-2017; 347 items
  Arrangement
  Alphabetically by last name of interviewee, then chronologically by program.
  Scope and Contents
  The Interviews, 1974-2017, series contains four subseries, including the interviews Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel produced for television broadcast; audio interviews that served as a basis for writing projects; video interviews made as part of the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Visiting Filmmakers Series at Duke in the 2010s, and two Conversations with Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel programs, with Roy Furman and Robert A.M. Stern, from 2014.
  - Broadcast video interviews, 1974-1994; 152 items
    The Broadcast video interviews, 1974-1994, subseries is comprised mainly of interviews, produced for broadcast by Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel, with members of New York's arts and architecture communities. The programs include About the Arts; American Architecture Now; Barbaralee Diamonstein and...; Fashion: The Inside Story; Handmade in America; Inside New York's Art World; Interior Design: The New Freedom; Visions and Images: American Photographers on Photography; as well as several interviews or programs independent of these series.
    Digital video preservation copies of the interviews were made from magnetic analog master tapes suffering from varying degrees of deterioration. Tapes were cleaned, and sometimes even baked at a low temperature, to stabilize the tape base long enough to create a digital transfer. Listed in this series are the tapes that were found to be most viable in creating the digital masters, but many of the interviews have multiple tape copies associated with them. To view the full tape inventory, please contact Rubenstein Research Services. Links to the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel YouTube Archive have been provided for access to the interviews.
    - Adolfo, Fashion: The Inside Story, 1984; 00:24:55 (Box AV-017, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0258)
      View on YouTube
    - Edward Albee, About the Arts, 1978; 00:28:23 (Box AV-043, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0424_01)
    - Emilio Ambasz, Interior Design: The New Freedom, 1981; 00:31:25 (Box AV-009, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0132)
    - Emilio Ambasz, American Architecture Now, 1983; 01:24:00 (Box AV-055, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0067)
    - Thomas Armstrong, Inside New York's Art World, 1976; 01:24:45 (Box AV-026, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0397)
    - Tom Armstrong, David Whitney, About the Arts, 1977; 00:29:41 (Box AV-003, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0035_01)
    - Edward Larrabee Barnes, Inside New York's Art World, 1979; 00:46:46 (Box AV-002, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0025)
    - Edward Larrabee Barnes, American Architecture Now, 1980; 01:09:06 (Box AV-001, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0015, Box AV-008, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0114)
    - Jonathan Barnett, John Portman, Richard Weinstein, American Architecture Now, 1980; 01:20:30 (Box AV-003, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0036_0037)
    - Kent Barwick, Hugh Hardy, Barbaralee Diamonstein and …, 1978; 00:29:42 (Box AV-003, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0039_01)
    - Romare Bearden, Inside New York's Art World, 1979; 00:53:44 (Box AV-013, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0199)
    - Ward Bennett, Interior Design: The New Freedom, 1981; 00:29:30 (Box AV-002, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0017)
    - Isabel Bishop, Inside New York's Art World, 1978; 00:59:52 (Box AV-018, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0268)
    - Bill Blass (edit), Inside Fashion, 1983; 00:23:04 (Box AV-024, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0352)
    - Bill Blass (uncut, timecode burned in), Inside Fashion, 1983; 01:49:51 (Box AV-062, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0133)
    - Dale Chihuly, Sam Maloof, John McQueen, Sandi Fox, Jack Lenor Larsen, Handmade in America, 1983; 00:29:19 (Box AV-021, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0321)
    - Robert Bray and Michael Schaible, Interior Design: The New Freedom, 1981; 00:30:38 (Box AV-007, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0101)
    - John Carter Brown, Inside New York's Art World, 1978; 00:36:11 (Box AV-018, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0266)
    - Mario Buatta, Interior Design: The New Freedom, 1981; 00:30:36 (Box AV-007, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0092)
    - Harry Callahan, Visions and Images: American Photographers on Photography, 1981; 00:30:47 (Box AV-015, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0228)
    - Cornell Capa, Inside New York's Art World, circa 1980; 01:02:24 (Box AV-004, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0055)
    - Cornell Capa and Burk Uzzle, Visions and Images: American Photographers on Photography, 1981; 00:30:22 (Box AV-012, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0200)
    - Anthony Caro, Inside New York's Art World, circa 1980; 01:02:31 (Box AV-005, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0075)
    - Leo Castelli, About the Arts, 1976; 00:29:13 (Box AV-001, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0010_01)
    - Schuyler Chapin, Barbaralee Diamonstein and …, 1977; 00:28:41 (Box AV-043, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0424_02)
    - Ivan Chermayeff, Inside New York's Art World, circa 1977; 01:02:32 (Box AV-015, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0223)
    - Dale Chihuly, Handmade in America, 1981; 00:26:07 (Box AV-005, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0071)
    - Christo and Jeanne-Claude, Inside New York's Art World, 1978; 00:25:54 (Box AV-014, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0204)
    - Chuck Close, Inside New York's Art World, 1978; 00:30:18 (Box AV-027, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0421)
    - Betty Comden, Adolph Green, Barbaralee Diamonstein and …, 1979; 00:29:07 (Box AV-006, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0077_02)
    - William Conklin, American Architecture Now, 1982; 00:25:17 (Box AV-011, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0163)
    - William G. Conway, Barbaralee Diamonstein and …, 1978; 00:30:17 (Box AV-014, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0206_01)
    - Lia Cook, Handmade in America, 1982; 00:16:54 (Box AV-013, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0191)
    - Maralin Niska, Frank Corsaro, Barbaralee Diamonstein and …, 1976; 00:28:58 (Box AV-014, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0208)
    - Merce Cunningham, About the Arts, 1977; 00:29:12 (Box AV-047, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0017)
    - Charlotte Curtis, About the Arts, 1976; 00:30:08 (Box AV-001, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0010_02)
    - Oscar de la Renta, Fashion: The Inside Story, 1984; 00:25:04 (Box AV-017, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0249)
    - Jim Dine, Inside New York's Art World, 1977; 00:28:43 (Box AV-013, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0194)
    - Jim Dine, Miscellaneous Interviews_Programs, 1982; 00:48:00 (Box AV-011, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0165)
    - Angelo Donghia, Interior Design: The New Freedom, 1981; 00:30:56 (Box AV-008, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0110)
    - Joseph Paul D'Urso, Interior Design: The New Freedom, 1981; 00:31:30 (Box AV-010, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0145)
    - I.M. Pei, Peter Eisenman, About the Arts, 1976; 00:30:31 (Box AV-043, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0422_02)
    - Peter Eisenman, Jack Robertson, American Architecture Now, 1984; 00:25:22 (Box AV-028, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0011)
    - Andre Emmerich, Nancy Graves, Inside New York's Art World, 1977; 00:22:36 (Box AV-023, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0381)
    - Elliott Erwitt, Visions and Images: American Photographers on Photography, 1981; 00:29:54 (Box AV-006, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0084)
    - Beverly Pepper, Sarah Faunce, Inside New York's Art World, 1979; 00:47:22 (Box AV-008, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0116)
    - Avery Fisher, Barbaralee Diamonstein and …, 1979; 00:29:44 (Box AV-024, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0338_01)
    - Sandi Fox, Handmade in America, 1983; 00:25:27 (Box AV-016, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0231)
    - Jacques Francais, Handmade in America, 1983; 00:25:36 (Box AV-010, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0138)
    - Robert Goelet, Henry Gardiner, Barbaralee Diamonstein and …, 1978; 00:30:05 (Box AV-014, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0207_01)
    - Frank Gehry, American Architecture Now, 1980; 00:51:45 (Box AV-017, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0253)
    - Henry Geldzahler, Barbaralee Diamonstein and …, 1978; 00:30:57 (Box AV-047, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0023)
    - Henry Geldzahler, Inside New York's Art World, undated; 01:01:19 (Box AV-011, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0166)
    - Brendan Gill, Barbaralee Diamonstein and …, 1978; 00:28:47 (Box AV-015, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0226_02)
    - Brendan Gill, Inside New York's Art World, 1978; 01:02:37 (Box AV-027, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0414)
    - Romaldo Giurgola, American Architecture Now, 1984; 00:58:53 (Box AV-010, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0147)
    - Milton Glaser, Inside New York's Art World, 1978; 00:27:35 (Box AV-012, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0171)
    - Louise Nevelson, Arnold Glimcher, Inside New York's Art World, 1977; 00:29:05 (Box AV-014, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0205)
    - Michael Graves, American Architecture Now, 1980; 01:20:12 (Box AV-003, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0031, Box AV-016, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0238)
    - Betty Parsons and Cleve Gray, About the Arts, 1977; 00:28:25 (Box AV-006, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0076_02)
    - John Guare, Albert Innaurato, Barbaralee Diamonstein and …, 1977; 00:28:49 (Box AV-003, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0033_01)
    - Charles Gwathmey, American Architecture Now, 1980; 00:56:48 (Box AV-016, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0242)
    - Richard Haas, Inside New York's Art World, circa 1978; 01:02:23 (Box AV-013, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0189)
    - Mark Hampton, Interior Design: The New Freedom, 1981; 00:31:03 (Box AV-022, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0337)
    - Hugh Hardy, American Architecture Now, 1980; 01:22:14 (Box AV-016, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0241, Box AV-002, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0022)
    - Kitty Carlisle Hart, Barbaralee Diamonstein and …, 1978; 00:29:52 (Box AV-014, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0207_02)
    - Pleasure and Principle: The Playboy Mystique, Pleasure and Principle: The Playboy Mystique, 1974; 00:29:28 (Box AV-016, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0233)
    - Alana Heiss, Richard Nonas, Inside New York's Art World, circa 1978; 01:01:23 (Box AV-005, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0063)
    - Thomas Hess, Inside New York's Art World, 1979; 01:01:10 (Box AV-073, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0237)
    - Jamake Highwater (Jackie Marks), Barbaralee Diamonstein and …, 1978; 00:30:16 (Box AV-065, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0163)
    - David Hockney, Inside New York's Art World, 1982; 01:24:31 (Box AV-015, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0224, Box AV-004, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0053, Box AV-002, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0030, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0029)
    - Horst P. Horst, Visions and Images: American Photographers on Photography, 1981; 00:29:41 (Box AV-012, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0178)
    - Thomas Hoving, Inside New York's Art World, circa 1978; 01:26:38 (Box AV-004, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0050, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0051, Box AV-010, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0151, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0152)
    - Robert Hughes, Alexander Liberman, Inside New York's Art World, circa 1978; 00:45:33 (Box AV-027, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0413, Box AV-008, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0117)
    - Robert Indiana, Inside New York's Art World, 1978; 00:28:50 (Box AV-025, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0358)
    - Hugh Jacobsen, American Architecture Now II, 1984; 00:25:19 (Box AV-014, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0213)
    - Philip Johnson, Inside New York's Art World, 1978; 01:02:15 (Box AV-011, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0167)
    - Philip Johnson, American Architecture Now II, circa 1984; 00:49:40 (Box AV-008, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0111)
    - Philip Johnson: Glass House Interview, 1994; 02:25:27 (Box AV-067, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0180_0181)
    - Ivan C. Karp, Inside New York's Art World, circa 1978; 00:51:06 (Box AV-015, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0219)
    - Herbert Kasper, Inside Fashion, 1984; 00:24:59 (Box AV-017, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0252)
    - Alex Katz, Inside New York's Art World, circa 1978; 01:00:40 (Box AV-010, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0143)
    - Joseph Kosuth, Leo Castelli, Inside New York's Art World, 1977; 01:06:37 (Box AV-023, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0386, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0380, Box AV-026, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0403)
    - Robert Kotlowitz, About the Arts, 1977; 00:28:49 (Box AV-065, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0159)
    - Lee Krasner, Inside New York's Art World, 1978; 00:28:42 (Box AV-010, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0144)
    - Peter Kreindler, Barbaralee Diamonstein and …, 1978; 00:30:08 (Box AV-016, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0232_01)
    - Jack Larsen, Handmade in America, 1982; 00:24:02 (Box AV-026, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0392)
    - Sarah Tomerlin Lee, Interior Design: The New Freedom, 1981; 00:30:52 (Box AV-002, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0016)
    - Alexander Liberman, Barbaralee Diamonstein and …, 1977; 00:29:18 (Box AV-006, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0076_01)
    - Roy Lichtenstein, Leo Castelli, Inside New York's Art World, 1977; 01:30:21 (Box AV-005, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0066, Box AV-023, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0382, Box AV-026, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0401, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0402)
    - William Lieberman, Inside New York's Art World, circa 1978; 00:57:55 (Box AV-005, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0065)
    - John Lindsay, Barbaralee Diamonstein and …, 1978; 00:29:31 (Box AV-003, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0035_02)
    - Louise Nevelson, Diana McKown, About the Arts, 1976; 00:29:40 (Box AV-052, Video-cassette RL10006-VHS-0047_01)
    - William Macomber, Barbaralee Diamonstein and …, 1978; 00:30:09 (Box AV-006, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0079_01)
    - Sam Maloof, Handmade in America, 1982; 00:22:41 (Box AV-014, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0201)
    - Mary McFadden, Fashion: The Inside Story, 1984; 00:25:04 (Box AV-017, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0251)
    - Marian McPartland, About the Arts, 1976; 00:29:41 (Box AV-043, Video-cassette RL10006-Umatic-0422_01)
    - John McQueen, Handmade in America, 1982; 00:25:23 (Box AV-007, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0095)
    - Richard Meier, American Architecture Now, 1980; 00:21:26 (Box AV-017, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0247)
    - Thomas Messer, Inside New York's Art World, 1978; 00:26:34 (Box AV-004, Video-cassette RL10006-UMATIC-0054)